Use of Solar Energy Conference papers, 1954-1957
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Use of Solar Energy Conference papers, 1954-1957
AZ 330
Administrative correspondence and related material regarding the planning and execution of the conference, including participants, registration, guests, program, finances, publicity, exhibits, preprints, and publication of reports and papers.
Conference on the Use of Solar Energy (1955: Tucson, Ariz.)
1.1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Association for Applied Solar Energy (AFASE), an organization created by industrial, financial, and agricultural leaders from Arizona sponsored a two part meeting in Arizona to bring attention to the issues of solar energy. The first part of the meeting was the Conference on the Use of Solar Energy: the Scientific Basis, held at the University of Arizona in October of 1955. This was followed by the World Symposium on Applied Solar Energy, held in Phoenix in November of 1955. Scientists and engineers from 36 countries attended these meetings. Additionally the Solar Furnace Symposium of 1957 was held in Phoenix.
Scope and Content Note
Administrative correspondence and related material regarding the planning and execution of the conference, including participants, registration, guests, program, finances, publicity, exhibits, preprints, and publication of reports and papers. In addition material dealing with the World Symposium on Applied Solar Energy held in Phoenix, Ariz., immediately following the conference, and the Solar Furnace Symposium of 1957, also held in Phoenix.
Access Terms
Solar energy -- Congresses
Correspondence
Separated Material
Conference proceedings received with the collection were removed and cataloged separately.
Container List
- Preliminary plans and committees. 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Edwin F. Carpenter and Stanford Research Institute. 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Edwin F. Carpenter, General. May-August 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Edwin F. Carpenter, General. September-December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Edwin F. Carpenter, General. 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Francis A. Roy, General. 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: University of Arizona President, Richard A. Harvill and Vice-President, R. N. Nugent. 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Program. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Participants and Guests (lists). (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: Prospective attendants. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Local arrangements. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Registration (forms, procedures, etc.). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Press, publicity, news releases. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Travel funds. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Financial records. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Pre-print sales. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Solar Engineering Exhibit, Phoenix, Arizona. 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Solar Furnace Symposium, Phoenix, Arizona: Program, proceedings, etc. January 21-22, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Solar Furnace Symposium, Phoenix, Arizona: Pre-prints. January 21-22, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Recordings of addresses, discussions, etc. (some with typescripts). (Box 3, Othertype 1-28)